Xevier Turrubiartes

Software Engineer

I am a software engineer proficient in JavaScript, React, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL. I have 4 years of experience in the financial services industry which allowed me to develop my assessment and communication skills with stakeholders and partners.

Austin, TX (713) 257-5582 xevierturrubiartes@gmail.com



inLinkedIn

EXPERIENCE

Siska Financial Services, Houston, TX — Financial Advisor

03/2015 - 10/2019

- Generated reports of various financial products, including stocks, bonds, mutual funds, and insurance policies; educated clients on benefits of individual products.
- Serviced accounts for more than 100 clients with over \$22 million in investment assets.
- Built and maintained relationships with clients by producing financial reports and summaries for the.
- Counseled clients on financial matters and provided recommendations on investment opportunities, products and services based on client needs and asset availability.
- Changed broker dealers requiring months of highly organized servicing for each account for each client.

Starbucks, Houston, TX — *Shift Manager*

10/2009 - 03/2015

- Trained and supervised staff members
- Facilitated on-site staff training and developed processes and procedures to increase accuracy

EDUCATION

Thinkful — Engineering Immersion

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

- Interactive web apps
- Server-side programming

University of Houston-Downtown — Bachelor of Business Administration

2018

SKILLS

JavaScript ES6

HTML5

CSS3

React

JQuery

Java

Node.js

PostgreSQL

Express

RESTful APIs

GitHub

Git

Client follow-up

Fluent in Spanish

PROJECTS

Neighbr App: LIVE APP

Client-side app

Tech: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS

Neighbr-API

Backend for Neighbr

Tech: Express, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

Spaced Repetition: LIVE APP

Client-side learning app

Tech: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS

Spaced Repetition-API

Backend for Spaced Repetition **Tech:** Express, NodeJS, PostgreSQL